<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>News - Kraiany</title>
  <subtitle>News and Press Releases. Kraiany - independent, non-governmental community of Ukrainians living in Japan.</subtitle>
  <id>https://www.kraiany.org/en/news.html</id>
  <link href="https://www.kraiany.org/en/news.html"/>
  <link href="https://www.kraiany.org/en/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2019-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Kraiany</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Kraiany Condemns Participation of so-called "DNR" in a Sporting Event</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.kraiany.org/en/news/2019-11-20-kwf-karate.html"/>
    <id>/en/news/2019-11-20-kwf-karate.html</id>
    <published>2019-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kraiany</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;According to several recent news sources, an event called "KWF World Conference &amp;amp; World Cup" took place in Tokyo during November 7-10, 2019.
http://kwfjapan.com/ , email: mail@kwf.jp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the sixth year, Ukraine has been in a state of undeclared war...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;According to several recent news sources, an event called "KWF World Conference &amp;amp; World Cup" took place in Tokyo during November 7-10, 2019.
http://kwfjapan.com/ , email: mail@kwf.jp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the sixth year, Ukraine has been in a state of undeclared war with the Russian Federation. The Russian Federation, having started the war with annexation of the Crimean peninsula, deceitfully occupied part of the territories of Ukraine in Donetsk and Luhansk regions, has been financing and sending regular military units to fight against an independent Ukrainian state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The so-called "Donetsk People's Republic (DNR)" and "Lugansk People's Republic (LPR)" are not recognized worldwide, and this is the official position of the Japanese government. In addition, under Ukrainian law, these so-called "republics" are recognized as terrorist organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the sports competition mentioned above did not go without political scandal. To participate in the competitions, athletes from the territories of Ukraine currently occupied by Russian Federation were issued entry visas to Japan, and were competing under the "flag" of the unrecognized "DNR”.
We condemn the action of the participants from the terrorist organization of so called “DNR”. We consider their actions as inadmissible, and visa obtained for participation in the event discredits work of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Japan. For this provocative actions we ask you to ban them entry to Japan in future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above is especially essential in the run-up to the 2020 Tokyo Olympics. In our view, it is extremely important not to make the same mistake when hosting world sports games.
On behalf of the Ukrainian community in Japan, we would like to ask you to resolve the incident to prevent such unfortunate mistakes from occurring in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
