<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>News - Kraiany</title>
  <subtitle>News and Press Releases. Kraiany - independent, non-governmental community of Ukrainians living in Japan.</subtitle>
  <id>https://www.kraiany.org/en/news.html</id>
  <link href="https://www.kraiany.org/en/news.html"/>
  <link href="https://www.kraiany.org/en/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2019-11-25T03:05:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Kraiany</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Ukrainian national costume exhibition was held in Tokyo</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.kraiany.org/en/news/2019-11-25-costume-2019.html"/>
    <id>/en/news/2019-11-25-costume-2019.html</id>
    <published>2019-11-25T03:05:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-11-25T03:05:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kraiany</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An exhibition of Ukrainian costumes was held on November 18-22 in the gallery of Bunka Gakuen in Tokyo. The exhibition presented 17 original costumes from 16 regions of Ukraine, as well as Rushnyk (embroidered cloth) from Central Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An exhibition of Ukrainian costumes was held on November 18-22 in the gallery of Bunka Gakuen in Tokyo. The exhibition presented 17 original costumes from 16 regions of Ukraine, as well as Rushnyk (embroidered cloth) from Central Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just a small part of a large collection of Olena Skrypka, who has been collecting these costumes for 25 years from all regions of Ukraine. We are very glad that we could showcase this collection in Japan, feel the Ukrainian color and get acquainted with the regional features of the costumes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the author of the collection, Olena Skrypka, she began to collect this collection because she felt an inner need to preserve and pass on to the next generations what was part of the identity for Ukrainians. The Ukrainian traditional costume carries the energy of generations and it is through it that you can see the bright and charming soul of the Ukrainian people. We must cherish and cherish this legacy in order to be one and strong nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lecture was held during the exhibition about the particulars of the Ukrainian costume, masterclasses for making Motanka (rag doll), beading and embroidery classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project was in preparation by the Ukrainian community in Japan for the last three years. We are very happy that this project has been realized thanks to the coordinated cooperation of the Embassy of Ukraine in Japan and Bunka Gakuen.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Demand for Annulment of Medals Earned by Members of Terrorist Organization "DNR"</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.kraiany.org/en/news/2019-11-23-kwf-medal-annulment.html"/>
    <id>/en/news/2019-11-23-kwf-medal-annulment.html</id>
    <published>2019-11-23T06:39:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-11-23T06:39:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kraiany</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;To: KARATENOMICHI WORLD FEDERATION&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Sir/Madam,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has come to our attention that during an event held by KWF on November 7-10, 2019, participants calling themselves "Donets People" or so-called "DNR" have been seen photographing themselves with...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;To: KARATENOMICHI WORLD FEDERATION&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Sir/Madam,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has come to our attention that during an event held by KWF on November 7-10, 2019, participants calling themselves "Donets People" or so-called "DNR" have been seen photographing themselves with a flag of the so-called "Donetsk People's Republic (DNR)".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 2013, Ukraine has been in a state of undeclared war with the Russian Federation for the sixth year. The Russian Federation, having started the war with annexation of the Crimean peninsula, deceitfully occupying part of the territories of Ukraine in Donetsk and Luhansk regions, has been financing and sending regular military units to fight against an independent Ukrainian state. The Russian Federation has also been regularly financing separatist movements via terrorist organizations that label themselves as "Donetsk People's Republic (DNR)" and "Luhansk People's Republic (LNR)".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These so-called republics are not recognized by the world community, which is also the official position of the Japanese government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Representing a terrorist organization and taking photographs with said symbolism is not acceptable. We condemn such actions taken by said participants, as it undermines Ukraine's sovereignty and territorial integrity. These actions also harm political image of Japan and the work done by the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Japan. It is regrettable to see that a Japanese national sport, Karate, is being used for Russian propaganda and disinformation against Ukraine and Japan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individuals identified to be members of “DNR” and seen at the event are the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Martynov Yurij Igorevich, (ru: Мартынов Юрий Игоревич, uk: Мартинов Юрій Ігорович) DOB: 1991/03/25&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Medvedev Andrej Valerevich (ru: Медведев Андрей Валерьевич, uk: Медведєв Андрій Валерійович) DOB: 1978/03/02&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Medvedeva Anna Anatolevna (ru: Медведева Анна Анатольевна, uk: Медведєва Ганна Анатоліївна) DOB: 1977/03/27&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To rectify the damage caused by illegal and irresponsible actions of said participants, we demand that KWF officials strip of the medals or certificates awarded to participants of the so-called "DNR". We further demand that said participants are barred from future competitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope our concerns are heard for the protection of Ukraine, as well as protection of Japanese image and spirit of Karate.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Kraiany Condemns Participation of so-called "DNR" in a Sporting Event</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.kraiany.org/en/news/2019-11-20-kwf-karate.html"/>
    <id>/en/news/2019-11-20-kwf-karate.html</id>
    <published>2019-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kraiany</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;According to several recent news sources, an event called "KWF World Conference &amp;amp; World Cup" took place in Tokyo during November 7-10, 2019.
http://kwfjapan.com/ , email: mail@kwf.jp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the sixth year, Ukraine has been in a state of undeclared war...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;According to several recent news sources, an event called "KWF World Conference &amp;amp; World Cup" took place in Tokyo during November 7-10, 2019.
http://kwfjapan.com/ , email: mail@kwf.jp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the sixth year, Ukraine has been in a state of undeclared war with the Russian Federation. The Russian Federation, having started the war with annexation of the Crimean peninsula, deceitfully occupied part of the territories of Ukraine in Donetsk and Luhansk regions, has been financing and sending regular military units to fight against an independent Ukrainian state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The so-called "Donetsk People's Republic (DNR)" and "Lugansk People's Republic (LPR)" are not recognized worldwide, and this is the official position of the Japanese government. In addition, under Ukrainian law, these so-called "republics" are recognized as terrorist organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the sports competition mentioned above did not go without political scandal. To participate in the competitions, athletes from the territories of Ukraine currently occupied by Russian Federation were issued entry visas to Japan, and were competing under the "flag" of the unrecognized "DNR”.
We condemn the action of the participants from the terrorist organization of so called “DNR”. We consider their actions as inadmissible, and visa obtained for participation in the event discredits work of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Japan. For this provocative actions we ask you to ban them entry to Japan in future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above is especially essential in the run-up to the 2020 Tokyo Olympics. In our view, it is extremely important not to make the same mistake when hosting world sports games.
On behalf of the Ukrainian community in Japan, we would like to ask you to resolve the incident to prevent such unfortunate mistakes from occurring in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
